Guide to the Scholarships Reference Collection, 1953-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Scholarships Reference collection 1953-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
0.5 linear feet Extent: 300 Items
UA.01.11.0027
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Complied by University Archives staff from campus mailings, clippings, and other sources for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
Collection includes materials concerning scholarships and fellowships awarded by the University and notable scholarships won by Duke students. Present are newspaper clippings, memoranda, notices, brochures, lists of scholarships, fellowships, and winners and other material. Scholarships include Alumni Association, Angier B. Duke, athletic, Barry M. Goldwater, Benjamin N. Duke, Braxton Craven, Churchill, Duke-North Carolina Honors, the Faculty Scholarship Fund, Fulbright, James B. Duke Fellowships, Luce, MacArthur, Madison, Marshall, Mellon, Nanaline Duke, North Carolina Scholarships, Presidential Fellowships, Reginaldo Howard, Rhodes, Richard M. Nixon, Robertson, Rotary Foundation, Trinity, Truman, University Scholars, and other awards.
See also scholarships and fellowships under department, programs and divisions.
Subject Headings
Andrew W. Mellon Foundation; Angier B. Duke Memorial Scholarship; Duke University -- Funds and scholarships; Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences -- Funds and scholarships; Fulbright scholarships; MacArthur Fellows Program; James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation (U.S.); Rhodes scholarships
Related Material
Alexander Memorial Fund records, 1970-1979.
University Archives, Duke University.
Awards Reference Collection, 1879-
University Archives, Duke University.
Legacy for tomorrow: Duke University scholarships in the Trinity College of Arts and Sciences and the School of Engineering.
University Archives, University Archives.
Office of the University Treasurer records, 1893-1982
University Archives, Duke University.
Student Project for University Development records, 1976-1979.
University Archives, Duke University.
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, Office of the Dean records, 1934-2003.
University Archive, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - General information, lists of scholarships (Box 1)
  - List of winners, 1953, 1998 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Alumni Association (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Angier B. Duke, clippings (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Angier B. Duke, printed matter (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Athletic (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Barry M. Goldwater, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Benjamin N. Duke, 1985- (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Braxton Craven, 1977- (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Cameron-Wade Scholarship Fund (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Churchill (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Duke/NC Honors (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Faculty Scholarship Fund (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Fulbright (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: James B. Duke Fellowship (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: James Madison Fellowship (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Luce (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: MacArthur Fellowship (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Marshall (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Mellon Fellowship (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Nanaline Duke (medical) (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Presidential (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Reginaldo Howard, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Rhodes (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Richard M. Nixon (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Robertson (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Rotary Foundation (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Trinity (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: Truman (Box 1)
  - Scholarships: University Scholars [Gates], 1999- (Box 1)
  - Duplicates, printed matter (Box 1)
  - Financial Aid (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Financial Aid Report, 1966-1967 (Box 1)